Teaming up with that
girl who ruined your career as a judge...
Are you a masochist,
or just trying to get lucky in your old age?
What did you say? Shut up!
Did you two sleep together?
Shut your filthy mouth!
You're a piece of shit,
but that doesn't mean everyone is as filthy as you!
Try me.
Come on, come on!
Bring it on!
You've finally lost it, Lao Yu.
How does it feel?
Feels pretty good, doesn't it?
Very amusing.
Let me tell you something.
There's no turning back now.
Do me a favor. Before making any decisions next time,
discuss it with me first.
Don't go acting on your own again.
If you do something stupid again,
I promise I'll show you
what unbearable consequences look like.
I had my own ideals too,
seeking value and meaning
when I joined this profession.
But reality is completely different.
I'm pretty conflicted myself.
Mr. Zhao.
You're still here?
Heading down for a drink?
Thank you for today.
It's nothing.
I...
want to take a couple of days off.
No problem.
Take a few extra days to rest.
Once you're fully rested,
you can visit Lao Kang in detention.
As a criminal defense lawyer,
with an organized crime case like this,
it's totally normal to wet your pants.
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
You know, when I first handled these cases,
I'd often get threatened by other gangs.
If you said even one wrong word,
a beating would be getting off easy.
I remember a former colleague
who was slashed over a dozen times.
Luckily, Lao Xu and I got him to the ER in time,
or it would have been a disaster.
But I digress.
Zhou Hao.
Come.
Have a drink and relax.
Come on.
You've been pampered since childhood.
I'm sure you have no shortage
of people who say nice things
to comfort you.
But you probably lack someone like me
who can tell you the truth.
Look.
Nice watch.
My dad gave it to me.
As a gift for becoming a lawyer.
I really envy you.
I remember
when I first started out as a lawyer,
I hadn't seen much of the world.
I only knew digital and quartz watches,
or ones you had to wind yourself.
I had no idea
there were six-figure mechanical watches
with an automatic winding function.
Do you know why I'm telling you this?
I don't want to rely on my dad.
I've always worked hard.
Right, worked hard.
Kids who grew up in your environment
are all spoiled.
Because you're always surrounded by people
who flatter you,
protect you,
and coddle you.
So you think
that with just a tiny bit of effort,
you deserve all that
applause, flowers, and success.
Because you're used to it.
But like people who wear digital watches
and those who wear mechanical ones,
they are blind to each other's worlds.
Look at you today.
When you are forced to
face confusion and the unknown,
your true colors show.
All that's left is fear,
wondering if you should just surrender.
In this life,
people do a lot to deceive themselves.
In your eyes,
you think being a lawyer,
fighting to the bitter end, is cool.
Taking the moral high ground is cool.
Not relying on your dad is even cooler.
It's not vanity.
Being a defense lawyer has meaning.
Right.
You wear a six-figure watch.
How often do you check it for the time?
Don't you still rely on your phone?
The "meaning" you speak of
is just packaging to make you feel better.
If you threw this watch away right now,
wouldn't you still live just fine?
It's not vanity.
But that female assistant of yours
is different from you.
Without pain and fear,
she couldn't survive.
Zhou Hao,
"meaning"
isn't just the icing on the cake.
Only when you truly feel
that it's your reason for living
does meaning have any value.
Mr. Zhao,
right now,
my mind is a mess.
Lao Kang has injuries.
He was beaten.
It might be a forced confession.
Zhou Hao.
I've already said so much to you.
Don't make me feel I'm wasting my breath.
Okay?
I'll ask you one last time.
Plead guilty and accept the penalty,
or fight for an acquittal?
Plead guilty.
I agree with Lawyer Zhou.
Let's do that.
Where's Zhou Hao?
The reason.
I explained it to you on the phone.
A family member got sick that day,
so I didn't go to the detention center,
and went straight home.
I don't mean why you went missing.
I mean
the reason for the sudden guilty plea.
Lao Kang pleaded guilty.
We have to respect the client's wishes.
Oh, really?
Have you seen Lao Kang in detention?
Are you sure
pleading guilty is what Lao Kang wants?
Then what about those obvious
loopholes in the evidence?
Can you stop being so aggressive?
I asked you here to help me.
What, you won't listen to me now?
Listen to you?
Yes, listen to me.
For Lao Kang's case,
the client has already pleaded guilty.
As defense lawyers,
we should respect the client's wishes.
Why are you refusing to let this go?
Are you trying to steal my spotlight?
Come on.
Or do you want to use this case
to get into Rujie directly?
Getting into Rujie is easy.
I can put in a good word for you.
But at the very least,
wait until I've secured my footing there.
What are you talking about?
Zhou Hao.
Did someone pressure you
to change the litigation strategy?
No.
No, Ding Ning.
Stop spending all your time
making up imaginary enemies for yourself.
There aren't that many enemies out there.
Not everyone is like you,
wanting to take on the whole world.
With the nursing home case,
haven't you learned your lesson?
I get it.
Xu Ruqing is handling the bribery charge.
Did Xu Ruqing say something to you?
Just because you have a father
who you think was wrongfully accused,
you habitually assume
that all your clients are innocent.
Meanwhile, you push everyone around you
into a corner.
Is that so?
Nobody owes you anything.
Is this Ding Ning?
Who's calling?
Hello, this is Zhao Yijie.
Yang Awu's adoptive father.
The actual client in Lao Kang's case.
Your phone number...
I had to beg Lao Yu for it.
Sorry if I'm being presumptuous.
It's fine.
I'm calling because...
How should I put this?
I'm a lawyer too.
So I know that
a client's family
shouldn't interfere with case strategy.
But Zhou Hao
has really gone a bit off track.
Anyway, I find
the idea of having Lao Kang plead guilty
a bit hard to accept.
I can't tell Zhou Hao directly,
because I'm his boss, after all.
Plus...
How about this?
I just got back from a business trip.
I'm going to Lao Yu's to pick up Yang Awu.
Would you like to have dinner with us?
Right at Lao Yu's place.
At Lao Yu's?
Lao Yu and I have been friends for years.
We talk about almost everything.
That you're staying at his place,
both Awu and Lao Yu
told me about it long ago.
So you don't need to avoid me.
You're heading home anyway.
Lao Yu...
has recently been treating Yang Awu
like his own child.
Once I pick him up today,
Lao Yu will have to go back
to living all by himself again.
So,
I think he might need you there.
What do you think?
See you at dinner.
Okay, see you at dinner.
Who is it?
I'm back.
Didn't I tell you
to stay at a hotel and not come back?
Didn't you get my text?
Is that so?
Ding Ning.
Awu.
I didn't check my phone.
Even though I have Alzheimer's,
I used to be a judge, you know.
I can tell when someone's lying.
Alright.
I need to see Zhao Yijie.
Why do you need to see him?
Zhou Hao is unreliable.
I need to win over Lao Kang's real client,
which is Zhao Yijie himself,
so I can switch to a not-guilty plea.
I know. I get it.
But I really don't want people gossiping.
You know?
Didn't you already tell them
that I'm staying at your place?
But...
Hello, little guy.
Don't run.
We finally meet.
Ning, come give me a hand.
Zhao Yijie.
Ding Ning.
Hello.
Here, this is for you.
Come on, Ding Ning.
Awu.
Awu, do you want this?
Go on, Awu.
Do you want it?
Play by yourself for a bit.
Awu, it's dangerous here in the kitchen.
Go sit on the couch for now.
No, it's fine.
It's more dangerous outside, right?
What do you want to eat?
We have... we have noodles.
I'll get you a bowl.
Okay.
You like noodles, don't you?
You're in for a treat with Grandpa.
It tastes pretty good.
But a bit bland.
Want some vinegar?
Awu, come have some shrimp.
You won't even eat shrimp?
Are you feeling unwell?
I shouldn't have taken you to the hospital.
The last time I had a home-cooked meal
was probably half a year ago.
These are all pre-packaged and takeout.
Anyone with hands can make them.
Don't be so dramatic, okay?
A home-cooked meal isn't about the food.
It's the home, right?
I think the four of us sitting here eating
feels a lot like a family.
Feels like a courtroom.
One judge, two lawyers.
How did you two meet?
Us two?
Lao Yu and I were in a case together.
But back then he wasn't a judge.
He was the victim's family.
Was it Mr. Yu's wife and son?
Yes, I was the lawyer for the second trial.
Speaking of which,
I've actually always felt regret over it.
Although I never met Mr. Yu's son,
I heard he was,
just like our Awu,
smart and lively.
And he really liked math, right?
He was good at sports too.
He played basketball exceptionally well.
Because I signed a letter of forgiveness,
I didn't have to attend the second trial.
I never even met you back then.
You seem to know my family pretty well.
Well, I'm a lawyer.
But later, we wished we'd met sooner.
What about you two?
Also because of a case.
So because of this case, you two...
What... what are you thinking?
Why keep bringing up the past?
Does it help with digestion?
I'm not bringing this up to be sad.
It's because I feel that
the four of us sitting here eating
should be grateful.
We've let go of superficial rivalries
to find similarities in our souls.
Souls?
Have you ever seen one?
I guess not.
I feel like with you, I also have this
feeling that we should've met sooner.
Actually, about Zhou Hao's case...
Awu,
are you full?
If you're full, go back to your room and play.
Go on.
Ding Ning, here's the thing.
Before that,
I'd like to discuss Xu Ruqing's case.
Is that okay?
Compared to Xu Ruqing's case,
I'd rather hear what happened to Zhou Hao.
As the client for Lao Kang's case,
I want to get a general understanding
of Lawyer Ding's abilities first.
By talking about one case?
Talking about one case
might not be enough to prove my skills.
So you're saying...
Ding Ning, is that pot of soup ready?
The soup you were making.
What are you doing? What do you want?
This is my home, not an office.
Who are you interviewing here?
We're just chatting.
What's there to chat about?
She's just an assistant lawyer.
Don't turn her into another Zhou Hao.
I know what you're plotting.
Alright.
Let me do it.
Okay, thanks.
So, what do you think of the legal profession?
Why do you always chat at the table?
Didn't your mother teach you?
No talking during meals or in bed.
It's basic manners.
We're all gathered here to eat.
Isn't it awkward if no one talks?
It is pretty awkward.
Right.
Look, Lao Yu.
Let me ask you a question, okay?
You've been a judge for most of your life.
Haven't you ever felt...
Felt what?
Anyway, I've been a lawyer for so many years.
I've long grown tired of many things.
I've long been numb to them.
I just wanted to ask Ding Ning.
Is she different from the two of us?
Who would be like you?
It's fine.
Ask whatever you want.
I often wonder to myself...
I just want to figure out...
exactly when did I start...
getting addicted to the legal profession?
You might say it's for money.
It's not.
For people with brains like ours,
going into finance or starting a business
would definitely earn more.
For power, then?
That's even less likely.
Taking crap from judges every day,
taking crap from prosecutors...
what power is there to speak of?
And it definitely isn't for the clients.
Clients are the craziest of all.
So, in the very beginning,
there must have been some kind of joy.
But what is this joy?
Definition.
What? Definition?
Right. The joy of definition.
At least for me,
being a lawyer is like doing research.
It is a form of creation.
Creation?
Discovering patterns in nature,
and defining those patterns.
That in itself is a form of creation.
I get it.
Just like mathematics.
It's a language of creation itself, right?
Exactly.
Literature uses words to map the world.
The difference between math and words
is that math uses numbers.
But fundamentally, they are the same.
They both create something out of nothing,
bridging the gap between us and the world.
What's this got to do with being a lawyer?
In a lawyer's world,
what we face is ambiguity,
gray areas, complexity, and disorder.
But only through definition
can we capture it.
Like defining someone's actions, motives,
or even consequences,
finding that often elusive
corresponding law.
Only then can order and simplicity return.
And a sense of order,
to some extent, is a sense of security.
So every messy case
is like a wild beast waiting to be tamed.
Perhaps that is the joy of it.
Brilliant.
Alright, I'm done eating.
Thank you all.
It's Tuesday, I have a meeting tonight.
I have to go now.
Awu,
let's go home with Dad.
Let Awu stay here.
Awu is feeling a bit unwell.
Didn't you say you were busy
with some regular meeting?
Don't make him run back and forth.
You can't take care of him anyway, right?
Alright, let's not put him through that.
I'll pick him up in a few days. Okay?
Okay.
I'll see you out.
As for Lao Kang's case,
come to my law firm tomorrow,
and we'll discuss it in detail.
Tomorrow?
See you tomorrow.
After deliberation by the collegial panel,
in defendant Kang Qingsong's robbery case,
the facts are clear, the evidence solid.
The court now renders its judgment:
All rise.
Defendant Kang Qingsong
is found guilty of robbery
and sentenced to four and a half years,
along with a fine of 5,000 RMB.
He is guilty of illegal firearm possession
and sentenced to two and a half years.
For the combined offenses,
he shall serve a total of six years,
along with a fine of 5,000 RMB.
If you do not accept this judgment,
after receiving the written judgment...
Are you sure
pleading guilty is what Lao Kang wants?
Then what about those
obvious loopholes in the evidence?
The accomplice's testimony,
the gun's serial number,
and the bullet evidence all match up.
He also pleaded guilty himself.
Do you still want to overturn his case?
one original copy
and two duplicate copies.
The sentencing is concluded.
Please be seated.
Bailiffs, please escort the defendant out.
I'm heading out.
Mr. Yu.
Xiao Sun.
Hello, hello.
Mr. Yu.
My first time...
Having you at my first ever criminal trial
means the world to me.
Don't mention it.
Keep it up. Keep working hard.
Did I do okay today?
You did. You did very well.
Thank you, Mr. Yu.
Let me buy you wontons tomorrow morning.
Let's do it another time.
I'm planning to take a trip soon.
To get some rest.
Then when you get back...
give me a call.
Okay, sure thing.
Okay.
Keep up the good work.
Take care, Mr. Yu.
Okay. Bye.
Hello, I'm Lawyer Zhao.
I know.
Follow me.
Lawyer Zhao, what's going on?
Rujie Lecture Hall.
Think of it as an internal study session.
Don't take it too seriously.
Treat it as a casual chat on any topic.
I'm not asking you
what kind of firm Rujie is.
I mean,
doing this leaves me totally unprepared.
What's the point if you're prepared?
You weren't prepared last night either.
But...
Alright, Ding Ning.
I'm driving right now.
Yang Awu is sick.
He insists on having a hometown dish.
I must pick up Yu Songfan for ingredients.
So,
handle the speech yourself, okay?
Wait.
You at least have to let me know
who exactly is out there listening to me.
Let me think...
Most are interns from top law schools.
And a few are
litigators from international courts.
Anyway,
I had Xu Ruqing gather everyone available.
Is it too late for me to leave?
Oh, come on.
I knew from the moment I met you
that we're the same kind of person.
You won't leave.
You're just shy.
I...
Hello everyone, I'm Ding Ning.
No profession
feels more isolating than being a lawyer.
We defend our clients time and time again.
Even if the justice system is friendly,
and public legal awareness is improving,
the nature of our profession dictates that
criminal defense lawyers must protect
the legitimate rights of their clients,
ensuring that all procedures
and evidence are legal and valid.
But in the eyes of the public,
it's a job of speaking for lawbreakers
and using that
to collect money and make a living.
How much hate we attract,
I won't go into detail here.
Over the past decade,
there have been over 110
defense lawyers sentenced to prison.
The defense rate in criminal cases
hovers around 30 percent.
Now, let's look at the income.
If you give up criminal law
and instead take on,
say, an IPO or M&A case,
charging two to three million is common.
But a criminal case only pays 30 to 50k.
and even a major case is only 150k.
So, why?
Being a defense lawyer is a rational job,
but when it comes to ourselves,
we are so irrational.
It doesn't make money, it's dangerous,
and the environment is unfriendly.
Yet we fight harder after every setback,
brainwashing ourselves into thinking
that this job
has all sorts of social meaning and value.
But more fundamentally,
for ourselves,
why do we do it?
Before I spout
some self-deceiving grand theories,
let me introduce myself again.
I work at a street-side law firm
converted from a karaoke bar.
Even a single meeting for a 200 yuan fee,
I'll take that kind of job.
My clients are usually
delivery drivers pressured by orders,
who snapped and smashed up a restaurant.
Or unemployed women
who became nannies to survive,
but were sexually assaulted,
and pushed the owner downstairs resisting.
And so on.
These are often
the cases you wouldn't bother to take.
But they're the soil I rely on to survive.
So I guess
Mr. Zhao Yijie invited me here
not because
I'm better at handling cases than you,
but to use a bottom-tier lawyer like me
to encourage you while spreading anxiety.
But I personally really hate
giving you all that kind of feeling.
So let's not let him succeed, okay?
Okay!
All right, just a little chit-chat.
What do you mean?
Keep this out of the wind.
It'll coagulate.
You gotta keep stirring it. Hurry.
How could...
a kid this young...
think of eating something so bloody?
When kids get sick, they get homesick.
Then they crave their hometown food.
What's so weird about that?
Didn't you see it just now?
They just took a live pig,
and from the cut... right here,
the blood kept dripping into this basin.
You think slaughtering a pig is cruel?
Isn't it?
Well, I don't see you being a vegetarian.
It's just like some people,
always saying how guilty they feel,
yet they still went to Judge Sun
to interfere with the verdict.
That's why people
are hypocritical with double standards.
Is Alzheimer's contagious?
Did I pass it on to you?
Don't you remember?
You told me to interfere with Judge Sun.
If it weren't for my grandson,
would I have done such a thing?
Even with Alzheimer's, you didn't forget
to get your grandson a paternity test.
Don't pigs have a lot of parasites?
There must be a ton in the blood.
How can anyone eat this?
Changing the subject
means you're happy with the results.
How's your Alzheimer's doing anyway?
Do you still get ringing in your ears?
Or you just can't remember numbers, right?
Why do you care so much?
Did you think of another dirty deed
you want me to do for you?
So even a judge like you
can have professional prejudice.
You always think we lawyers
rely entirely on connections,
and set traps to win cases, right?
That we're all up to no good, right?
Don't say that.
I never said that.
Not all lawyers.
Just a lawyer like you.
You're no stranger to breaking the law.
Who framed Lao Kang?
Should I give you a medal?
Stop throwing the word "crimes" around.
When it comes to Lao Kang,
we're accomplices now.
We're comrades-in-arms.
Just like the butcher who killed the pig.
The only difference between you and me is
that you only dare to kill blindfolded.
Who blindfolded me,
and used my hand to kill the pig for him?
Open your eyes right now!
Grandpa.
What's wrong with you?
The pig blood you wanted spilled.
There's nothing left to eat.
Why do you want to eat such weird things?
Tell me.
Grandpa.
Look.
I finished drawing the wound.
What?
Lan.
What does "Lan" mean?
Home.
We can see the tree friends when we go home.
All right.
Grandpa will take you home.
To see your tree friends, okay?
Let's go.
Come on.
Please continue.
Mr. Xu.
Mr. Zhao.
Attorney Ding.
You...
really spoke brilliantly just now.
I'm flattered.
About those...
can you send me those case files?
Sure. I'll send you a copy later.
If you have any questions later,
feel free to contact me anytime.
Congratulations on joining Rujie.